clicktogive.com 2012-10-03

# Click to Give - Privacy Policy

ClickToGive.com is committed to respecting the privacy rights of users of the Website (all capitalized terms not defined in this notice have the same meanings as in ClickToGive.com’s Website Terms of Use, which is incorporated herein by reference). ClickToGive.com created this Privacy Policy to give You confidence as You visit and use the Website, and to demonstrate its commitment to fair information practices and to the protection of privacy.

This Privacy Policy is only applicable to the Website and not to any Third-Party Websites, which may have data collection, storage and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Privacy Policy. For additional information, see the section concerning Third-Party Websites, below.

BY USING THE WEBSITE, YOU REPRESENT AND WARRANT THAT YOU HAVE READ AND UNDERSTOOD, AND AGREE TO THE TERMS OF, THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND OR DO NOT AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU MUST IMMEDIATELY LEAVE THE WEBSITE.

Each time You use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply. Accordingly, each time You use the Website You should check the date of this Privacy Policy (which appears at the end) and review any changes since the last time You used the Website. For additional information, see the section concerning Updates and Changes to Privacy Policy, below.

## **1) INFORMATION COLLECTION PRACTICES  
**

## ** a) Traffic Data.**

Like most website operators, ClickToGive.com automatically gathers information of the sort that browsers automatically make available, including: (i) IP addresses; (ii) domain servers; (iii) types of computers accessing the Website; and (iv) types of Web browsers accessing the Website (collectively “Traffic Data”). Traffic Data is anonymous information that does not personally identify You.

## **b) Cookies.**

A "Cookie" is a string of information that a website stores on a user’s computer, and that the user’s browser provides to the website each time the user submits a query to the website. The purpose of a Cookie is to identify the user as a unique user of the Website. ClickToGive.com uses Cookies to customize Your experience on the Website to Your interests, to ensure that You do not see the same advertisements or informational messages repeatedly, and to store Your password so You do not have to re-enter it each time You visit the Website. For additional information on ClickToGive.com’s uses of Cookies, see the section concerning Information Use and Disclosure Practices/Traffic Data and Information Gathered Using Cookies, below.

IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO HAVE COOKIES PLACED ON YOUR COMPUTER, YOU SHOULD SET YOUR BROWSERS TO REFUSE COOKIES BEFORE ACCESSING THE WEBSITE, WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT CERTAIN OF THE SERVICES AND CERTAIN FEATURES OF THE WEBSITE MAY NOT FUNCTION PROPERLY WITHOUT THE AID OF COOKIES. IF YOU REFUSE COOKIES, YOU ASSUME ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY RESULTING LOSS OF FUNCTIONALITY. 

## **c) Personal Information.**

In order for You to use certain of the Services, You may be asked to provide ClickToGive.com certain information that personally identifies You (“Personal Information”). Personal Information includes, without limitation Your email address. In each case, You will be asked to provide Personal Information; the Website will not gather it surreptitiously. You are under no obligation to provide Personal Information, with the caveat that Your refusal to do so may prevent You from using certain of the Services.

## **2. INFORMATION USE AND DISCLOSURE PRACTICES**

## **a) Traffic Data and Information Gathered Using Cookies**

ClickToGive.com analyzes Traffic Data and information gathered using Cookies to help ClickToGive.com better understand who is using the Website and how they are using it. By identifying patterns and trends in usage, ClickToGive.com is able to better design the Website to improve Your experience, and to serve You more relevant and interesting content and advertisements. From time to time, ClickToGive.com may release Traffic Data and information gathered using Cookies in the aggregate, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the Website. ClickToGive.com does not attempt to link information gathered using Cookies to Personal Information.

## **b) Personal Information**

Generally. ClickToGive.com uses Your Personal Information to send You information about ClickToGive.com and to contact You when necessary in connection with the Services.

## **c) Disclosure Practices**

Except under the following circumstances, ClickToGive.com will keep Your Personal Information private, and will not sell or otherwise share it with third parties:

**Disclosure in Connection with Services.**  ClickToGive.com discloses Personal Information to those who help it provide Services, including those who perform technical, administrative and data processing tasks such as hosting, billing, fulfillment, and data storage and security.

**By Law or to Protect Rights.**  ClickToGive.com discloses Personal Information when required to do so by law, or in response to a subpoena or court order, or when ClickToGive.com believes in its sole discretion that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of ClickToGive.com, third parties or the public at large. 

**Business Transfers; Bankruptcy.  **ClickToGive.com reserves the right to transfer all Personal Information in its possession to a successor organization in the event of a merger, acquisition, or bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of ClickToGive.com’ assets. Other than to the extent ordered by a bankruptcy or other court, the use and disclosure of all transferred Personal Information will be subject to this Privacy Policy, or to a new privacy policy if You are given notice of that new privacy policy and an opportunity to affirmatively opt-out of it. Personal Information submitted or collected after a transfer, however, may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by ClickToGive.com’ successor organization.

## **3. SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

ClickToGive.com has implemented and maintains reasonable security procedures and practices to protect against the unauthorized access, use, modification, destruction or disclosure of Your Personal Information.

## **4. DAILY REMINDERS**

You may subscribe to receive ClickToGive.com daily reminders. Each daily reminder has clear instructions about how to unsubscribe. Should You subscribe to the daily reminders and later wish to unsubscribe, You can opt-out of receiving the daily reminders at anytime by following the unsubscribe instructions contained therein.

## **5. THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES**

ClickToGive.com neither owns nor controls Third-Party Websites. Accordingly, Third-Party Websites are under no obligation to comply with this Privacy Policy except with respect to Information provided directly to them by ClickToGive.com. Before visiting or providing Personal Information to a Third-Party Website, You should inform Yourself of the privacy policies and practices (if any) of that Third-Party Website, and should take those steps necessary to, in Your discretion, protect Your privacy.

## **6. SURVEYS**

From time to time, ClickToGive.com may ask You to participate in surveys designed to help ClickToGive.com improve the Websites or Services. Any Personal Information provided to ClickToGive.com in connection with any survey will be used only in relation to that survey, and will be disclosed to third parties not bound by this Privacy Policy only in aggregated form.

## **7. UPDATES AND CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, ClickToGive.com reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, update, change or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such update, change or modification on this page. Any such addition, update, change or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Website. Each time You use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply. Accordingly, each time You use the Website You should check the date of this Privacy Policy (which appears at the end) and review any changes since the last time You used the Website. Unless ClickToGive.com obtains Your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after the effective date of such revised Privacy Policy, and not to information collected under any earlier Privacy Policy.

Effective Date: 13 Nov 2010
